Who's your first round pick?
>> Not at all.
>> The volume play. You know what I mean?
>> There you go.
>> James, um, if you could come up with a
theme maybe for this year's drive class,
what would it be?
>> Yeah, I think it was exactly that. It
was uh higher volume of draft capital
and ensuring that we could prioritize
guys that match and align with what I've
spoke a lot about which are the
intangible elements, the elements that
don't necessarily always lie on the
surface but are beneath the hood. And I
think it's very clear internally that uh
we were able to do just that and really
excited about what lies in front.
>> When you look at a guy like Parker
Hughes, you nab him with your last draft
pick. What what do you see? What what
jumps out at you? Oh man, there's a ton
to to point to. Obviously, you know, the
fact that he's somebody who can run very
fast, find the football, track it down,
and get ball carriers uh on the ground
is going to be really helpful to our
cause. And, you know, I got to give our
our coaching staff, our scouting staff
who in collaboration uh monitor the
undrafted college free agent landscape
and prioritize guys at each position.
And there was a lot of heat uh from not
only position coaches but also our
special teams coaches and our scouting
staff coming into the process uh that
made sure that he was never an
afterthought and somebody that over the
course of uh this past month Liam myself
and camp were able to really become
intimate and understanding what he would
offer uh and be able to towards the end
of the draft feel good about submitting
his name. James, uh, James, the state of
your starting lineup, but also your 2D
coming into the weekend. Did that not
did that allow you guys to maybe take
some more developmental prospects today,
especially that you can just spend this
year, you know, uh, smoothing out the
rough edges?
>> Yeah, you know, I feel good about these
guys that we've we've selected or have
in fact agreed to terms with and
undrafted college free agency uh,
competing for spots and doing their part
to level up our play and the competition
across the roster. uh while at the same
time knowing that there's going to be
some development required for sure. And
uh really knowing that those guys are
are going to pour into it. And you know,
we're not going to invite anybody into
this building uh who isn't a strong
match for it. And you know, the the idea
that those that we have uh are in fact
built to thrive and be the best versions
of themselves because of the the
environment and and that alignment with
what they're actually built of and made
of, I think, is uh is really clear in
this crop.
Go ahead.
>> Back to Parker. A, who found him? B, in
terms of linebacker, offball linebacker
philosophy, looking back at your time
with the Rams,
>> where things stand now through two draft
cycles, in terms of the priority at the
offball linebacker position, where you
have found value, how would you evaluate
that?
>> Yeah, you know, so to go to the first
portion of that question, just like with
any uh the prospects, it typically comes
from uh the the area scout. And so A-Rod
did a great job bringing his name to the
table early in the down and had a ton of
heat uh which ultim ultimately funneled
uh upward uh for our cross check to then
our undrafted college free agency
committee and then ultimately through
that uh layered portion of interest uh
up to coordinator level myself and Liam.
Um so that's kind of the the transition
of uh ultimately his viewing and
interest level. But um as it relates to
the second portion of that question, uh
certainly think you can find quality
players at a ton of different intervals
and we certainly had success towards the
latter half and uh latter portion of
drafts and also undrafted college free
agency in Los Angeles uh specifically at
the linebacker position. Uh, but
nonetheless, I think that instincts are
certainly going to be something that
reigns supreme in that space, knowing
that a lot happens fast and in the
specific interest of of Parker, uh, that
stands out in a real way.
>> What you like about Wesley?
>> A ton. I mean, that dude gets after it.
he's got uh the makeup that aligns with
everything that we covet. And the fact
that he's able to disrupt both the run
and the pass uh is really a helpful
piece to our cause because we don't want
to be too onedimensional defensively and
in particular we want to stop the run
and uh knowing that he can do his part
to disrupt uh while at the same time uh
maintain uh fundamentals and techniques.
Uh it's a really exciting piece.
>> Five block kicks for him too.
>> Oh, it's impressive. And I know like I
went and watched those specifically
towards the latter half of last week
because I hadn't stumbled into them. I
just stumbled into uh something that we
called did you know and it was a little
nugget that our analytics crew uh puts
together on each player. And so as I'm
just reading I was like you know what
I've watched all of his defensive snaps,
all of his games but let me go watch
these kick block kicks specifically. him
uh and then it forced me to go back and
actually watch his special team snaps
and even on uh a number of the kicks
that he didn't block, he was creating
disruption and getting really close in a
lot of instances as well. So that's
certainly uh more than just uh happen
stance. It's a unique piece that he
offers.
>> Why is he good at it?
>> It's hard to explain. I know he cares.
Uh so that's probably the first thing
because you know so many guys have
talent, but the mindset's the
differentiator. And I think in that
instance, it's certainly something that
I I think plays it part.
>> CJ Williams said he knew the Jags were
interested enough to go back and watch
every game from last season.
>> What did you find about CJ and your
research on him?
>> That is I did not know that nugget. that
is I I felt like I held that one close
to the vest, but uh nonetheless, I think
he fits the bill for a lot of the things
that I've long appreciated in wide
receiver play. Uh with both the the guys
that we drafted at the position, uh they
are extremely tough, extremely good
blockers. Uh they are extremely good at
attacking the football. Uh so really
excited about both him and Josh entering
the fray. with Josh 528 pound squat.
>> Oh man, that's impressive.
>> Have you seen that on film?
>> I have not seen that, but I have watched
his football play and I can understand
how he's able to do that when he's got
five guys on his back and he's still
standing. So that's uh that's not all
that surprising, but yeah, he is an
impressive human being.
>> Couple walk-ons late, college walk-ons.
What does that tell you about?
>> Couple walk-ons early. You know, you got
to love it. I think that that is a part
to me that uh says a lot if you can
start there and end in the conversation
of being a potential draft pick. It says
a lot about uh what you can overcome,
being able to, you know, when your
back's against the wall, be able to find
your your path to success and uh
certainly something that we think about
when we're prioritizing guys.
>> How does Tanner fit?
I think very clearly he's got a
superpower that he offers in a real way
and that's catching the football. Uh
obviously his production over the course
of his college tenure speaks volumes. Uh
being one of if not the most productive
pass catcher uh in college history
depending on how you look at things and
uh I think for how we operate for how
Trevor um best operates having a a big
target like that isn't a bad thing
especially when it comes to red zone
play. You mentioned the theme was
volume. Did you go in with that plan?
Like was that always in your head that
you wanted to get as many draft picks
and maybe not move around as much?
>> Yeah, that was uh a big piece to even my
walk through in the interview process.
The higher volume of draft capital was
what we were seeking and knowing that
the more at bats you have, the better
probability uh you'll have for for
successful selections while at the same
time uh you can have a few more hit uh
misses than you do hits. But
nonetheless, uh it was cool to lean into
that as a part of this draft. And uh I
know with 10 more that lie in front of
us in 2027 as it stands, we're going to
have a healthy three-year run in terms
of count.
>> What was your uh favorite or most
memorable call from this past three
days?
>> Oh man, I don't know if I can say that
on on air. There there were definitely
some entertaining moments. Uh you always
appreciate those calls. uh knowing that
they can be uh so meaningful for the
guys that are across the line. And you
know, while there were a ton of emotions
uh for them, there were also a ton of
emotions on our end. and to see our
coaching staff, our scouting staff who
have poured in a ton of time and energy
uh into coming to ultimately a big
decision. Uh it's really just a moment
where I I find myself being grateful uh
moment of gratitude to to be able to be
the one to dial. Um but it's certainly a
meaningful meaningful moment and the
most entertaining ones I'll probably
have to keep offline. Now that your
second draft class is done, how much
different was this process compared to
your first one last year?
>> You know, I think uh certainly efficient
in comparison uh not being in a position
where you have to translate two
different systems uh two different
languages. Uh it just allows lines of
communication to be far more fluid. And
so I think that was a really helpful
piece to to our process and uh one that
I have to imagine will only continue to
get more refined and better as we move
forward.
>> James, how do you compare?
>> Uh gosh, I want to say three weeks ago
was when I really poured in. Uh that was
another one where uh our area scout had
a ton of interest. um our undrafted
college free agent committee uh surfaced
him to the top and got us really pouring
in at a deeper level across our over the
top scouts uh coordinator level, myself
and Liam. Um and then if I'm not
mistaken, he ended up being uh the
player that was listed in that annual
article um of go ahead and figure out
who this guy is. And uh Brian Xanders
ended up knocking on my door and after
reading it said, "Hey, you know what? I
think uh I think he may be somebody that
is going to become more publicly aware
here soon or may become of interest to
others if they're able to figure it out
as well. Um but nonetheless certainly
excited to bring him into the into the
organization knowing that he's got uh
really a cool background, you know, and
one that um is not all that different
than some of the others that we drafted
and overcoming the odds and earning
their place. and uh you know he was
really really effective in rushing the
pass or creating disruption this past
season.
>> James, how do you compare what you got
out of this draft to what you wanted to
get out of it?
>> Oh, that's a great question. Uh so I can
say as a part of maybe the day before uh
kickoff on Thursday, we ended up putting
players in slots across all 11 picks.
And uh can in fact say that uh we were
able to nail 10 of those 11 and we only
made 10 selections. So uh that was a
pretty fun outcome knowing that we were
able to map it uh as cleanly as we were.
I don't think that uh had anything to do
with skill, but maybe a little more luck
than that. But uh that was a pretty
exciting piece.
>> When guys are transferring schools so
much more now than 5 10 years ago, does
that make the process for you guys, a
scouting process and investigation
process any harder or any more difficult
than it used to be?
>> It makes it interesting. It makes it a
little bit more of a chase while at the
same time, you know, I when guys are
only in one place for a short period of
time, you may not get a full picture.
So, it's only a glimpse typically. So,
you'd like for there to be uh a little
bit more of a long-term standing uh
position for you to source intel from
and not just a someplace that they may
have stopped, not just called some
version of of a stay, but I think it
helps when people are really intimate
with the player that you're you're
listening to their perspective on. Um,
and so that bouncing around can make it
a little more challenging. Well, at the
same time now you get a few different
more perspectives on the matter. So, uh
I don't think it hurts uh so to speak,
but uh yeah, it definitely makes the
chase a little bit more entertaining.
>> Back to kind of mapping out the draft.
Have you ever done that before? I mean,
your time in LA last season was been
able to do it.
>> That was a fun exercise this year. And
um
>> I can say to a certain degree I would uh
but I wasn't making the decisions in Los
Angeles. So that was uh probably more on
my own or off to the side. Um whereas
this one was obviously I had a little
bit more control over what direction we
actually went. Uh I know that Jake does
that on his own, Jake Tam. and it's fun
to uh look over and cross reference uh a
larger list of players that he would
love to choose from and uh have that be
a part of the the conversation. But
yeah, that was a a unique one for this
this cycle.
>> Did you expect to be able to hit it like
that?
>> No. No. So that was fun. That was a
blast. Yeah, Liam and I were just
laughing about it that, you know, that
was an oddity. I think I think that was
an outlier. I wouldn't anticipate that
being the case even moving forward. I
feel like I asked this last year, but
how would you evaluate evaluate your
pass rush after three days of getting
NFL draft?
>> That's hard to say that it's any
different than where it was uh you know
towards the end of last season. And I
think the exciting thing from my vantage
point is we got some really good
football players across that defensive
front and our scheme is prepped to tie
not only the rush plan but also the back
end coverage together in a way that's
going to make that really impactful.
>> Cameron Cameron had the left ankle.
Will he be healthy for all these guys?
>> Yeah, that could impact uh just how
quickly he's able to hit the ground
running. Uh we'll assess that a little
more closely upon arrival, but uh it's
fair question because it could in fact
delay his start to on the grass play.
>> Everybody else good to go.
>> Everybody else is good to go.
Thank you, James.